{"tossups": [{"question": "John Cobb died while on a speedboat in this body of water. The crannog of Cherry Island lies in this body of water, on whose shores lie Urquhart Castle and the town of Port Augustus. The Falls of Foyers feed into this body of water. The \u201cSurgeon\u2019s Photograph\u201d was a hoax purportedly depicting a creature that lived in this lake. For ten points, name this Scottish body of water, purportedly home to a cryptocreature named Nessie.", "answer": "<b> Loch Ness</b> (or<b> Lake Ness</b>)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "This island\u2019s native population, known for long, wavy beards, rebelled in Shakushain\u2019s Revolt. This island\u2019s port of Hakodate [hah-ko-dah-tay] was the capital of its breakway Republic of Ezo. The first Asian Winter Olympics were held on this island at Sapporo. The Seikan Tunnel connects this home of the Ainu people to its southern neighbor, Honshu. The Sea of Okhtosk is north of, for ten points, what northernmost of Japan\u2019s four main islands?", "answer": "<b> Hokkaido</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "Marty Glickman claimed that his removal from an Olympic team in favor of this man was a political capitulation by Avery Brundage. This man provided the \u201cgreatest 45 minutes in sports\u201d by breaking three world records and tying another at a Big Ten conference meet. This athlete controversially claimed that \u201cit was our president who snubbed me\u201d in response to having not shaken Adolf Hitler\u2019s hand on the medal podium. For ten points, name this African-American runner who won four gold medals at the 1936 Summer Olympics.", "answer": "(James Cleveland) Jesse<b> Owens</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {}, {"question": "After fighting at Sevastopol, this city was to be attacked by the Schwerer Gustav railgun. An attack on this city was led by Ritter von Leeb and carried out during Operation Northern Light. A supply route called the Road of Life helped resupply this city by ferrying supplies across Lake Lagoda. During the relief of this city, the Baltic fleet fired on troops from Army Group North after breaking 900 days of siege. For ten points, name this city, named for the first leader of the Soviet Union.", "answer": "<b> Leningrad</b> (prompt on St. Petersburg before mentioned; do not accept or prompt Petrograd)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "The aphorism\u201cearly to bed, early to rise/makes a man healthy, wealthy, and wise\u201d is attributed to, for ten points, what author of<em> Poor Richard\u2019s Almanac</em>, an American founding father?", "answer": "Ben<b> Franklin</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Misc Literature"}, {}, {"question": "Wisconsin\u2019s John Blaine was the only senator to vote against ratification of this agreement, which the Senate interpreted to protect the right to self-defense. Sixty-two countries ultimately signed this agreement, which was criticized for having no effective means of enforcement, as seen by Italy\u2019s invasion of Ethiopia in 1935. For ten points, name this 1928 agreement, named for a US Secretary of State and French Foreign Minister, whose signatories renounced the use of war in national policy.", "answer": "<b> Kellogg-Briand</b> Pact (accept<b> Pact of Paris</b>) <b>Second Quarter</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Childe Wills, Joseph Galamb, and Eugene Farkas designed this product, which was \u201clarge enough for the family, but small enough for the individual to run and care for.\u201d Scraps of wood from its production led to the formation of Kingsford Charcoal. After six years of production, its inventor decided it can be\u201cpainted any color [the customer] wants, so long as it\u2019s black.\u201d Factories in Highland Park and Detroit made, for ten points, what affordable automobile that was phased out by Ford in 1927 in favor of the Model A?", "answer": "Ford<b> Model T</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "One side\u2019s monarch in this war was captured at the Skirmish at Bender. Grengam and Gangut were two major naval battles in this war, in which Augustus the Strong was defeated. The Cossack leader Ivan Mazeppa switched sides in this war, which was ended by the Treaty of Nystad. One side attacked in a blinding snowstorm to win the Battle of Narva in this war, though Charles XII would later be defeated at Poltava by Peter the Great. For ten points, name this early 18th century war in which Russia soundly defeated Sweden.", "answer": "<b> Great Northern</b> War", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "In this region, Rachel Corrie was run over by a bulldozer while trying to prevent a house demolition. Ariel Sharon launched a unilateral disengagement from this region, which is home to the currently defunct Yasser Arafat International Airport. In 2014, Operation Protective Edge was launched against this region after the kidnapping and murder of three teenage Israeli settlers. Hamas currently controls, for ten points, what Mediterranean-bordering \u201cstrip\u201d once held by Israel?", "answer": "<b> Gaza</b> Strip (prompt on answers mentioning Palestine)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This country\u2019s navy was the target of Operation Praying Mantis in retaliation for its mine striking the USS<em> Samuel B. Roberts</em>. Terrorists killed 422 people in the Cinema Rex fire, which was blamed on SAVAK, this country\u2019s secret police. Allan Dulles planned Operation Ajax to remove Mohammed Mossadegh from power in this country, from where Reza Pahlavi was exiled. For ten points, name this country where a 1979 revolution brought Ayatollah Khomeini to power in Tehran.", "answer": "<b> Iran</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This character claims to possess an \u201citemized list of thirty years of disagreements\u201d in one appearance. One character aggravatedly notes that this man wrote 51 separate essays in a work that was only supposed to run 25 total essays. This character is introduced as a \u201cbastard orphan\u201d in the opening song of his musical, which is narrated by his eventual assassin, Aaron Burr. For ten points, name this protagonist of a 2015 Lin-Manuel Miranda musical and first Secretary of the Treasury.", "answer": "Alexander<b> Hamilton</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Misc Arts"}, {}, {"question": "This man addressed the Shell Crisis during World War I as Minister of Munitions, and he succeeded Lord Kitchener as Secretary of State for War in 1916. This only Prime Minister to have spoken fluent Welsh was among the \u201cBig Four\u201d at the Versailles Conference. For ten points, name this Liberal British Prime Minister who presided over the end of World War I.", "answer": "David<b> Lloyd George</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This author wrote a work subtitled \u201cThe Long Parliament\u201d about the English Civil War. Another work by this author states that \u201cdark and erroneous doctrines\u201d are used by a \u201cconfederacy of deceivers\u201dto help create a \u201cKingdom of Darkness.\u201d That work by this author states that there only exist three types of commonwealth, of which absolute monarchy is the best option. For ten points, name this author who described life as \u201cnasty, brutish, and short\u201d in<em> Leviathan</em>.", "answer": "Thomas<b> Hobbes</b>", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man forced Henri, duc de Rohan, to agree to the Peace of Alais. Pere Joseph was a prominent ally of this man, nicknamed for the grey robe that he wore as a Capuchin friar.</b> <b>(+)</b> <b>Marie de Medici\u2019s exile was due to her involvement in a conspiracy to remove this</b> <b>leader, the Day of the Dupes. The siege of the Huguenot castle of La (*)</b> Rochelle was led by this man, who was also known as the \u201cRed Eminence\u201d. He was succeeded by Mazarin in his highest post. For ten points, name this powerful chief minister of Louis XIII, a French cardinal.", "answer": "Cardinal<b> Richelieu</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>This year was the last time a major party was undecided on its Presidential nominee at the start of the convention. One presidential candidate in this election year defeated Arizona senator Morris Udall in the primaries, and gave an interview admitting that he had (+)\u201clust in his heart.\u201d The incumbent in this race was damaged by his assertion that there was \u201cno Soviet domination of Eastern Europe\u201d and his (*) </b> pardoning of Richard Nixon for Watergate. For ten points, name this election year in which Gerald Ford was defeated by peanut farmer Jimmy Carter?", "answer": "Presidential election of<b> 1976</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>This region was occupied during the Lesser Wrath of 1743 after the Hats\u2019 War. An 1866 famine in this nation and its western neighbor was the last naturally caused one in Europe. After World War II, this country secured its safety by signing the (+) YYA Treaty with its larger, eastern neighbor, which this country fought in the Continuation and Winter Wars. A (*)</b> sniper from this country was nicknamed the \u201cWhite Death\u201d for his kill count and helped avenge this country\u2019s loss of Karelia to the USSR. For ten points, name this Scandinavian country with capital at Helsinki.", "answer": "<b> Finland</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This work concludes by recommending \u201can increasing sense that a thing won by breaking the rules of the game is not worth the winning.\u201d It notes how \u201cthe speculative character of</b> <b>the business would be done away with\u201d if its subject was able to control the (+)</b> <b>shipping</b> <b>and refining aspects of production. This work grew out of interviews with Henry Rogers, and was followed by a two-part profile of its subject\u2019s CEO. (*)</b><em> McClure\u2019s</em> magazine published a serialized version of, for ten points, what 1904 muckraking expos\u00b4e by Ida Tarbell into the inner workings of John D. Rockefeller\u2019s company?", "answer": "The<b> History of</b> (the)<b> Standard Oil</b> Company (accept any answer that mentions the<b> History </b>of<b> Standard Oil</b>, ignoring the usual \u201cthe title must be exact\u201d rule, as it\u2019s been published under many permutations; do not prompt on Standard Oil alone)", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Other Social Science"}, {"question": "<b>One performer of this instrument, who wrote \u201cNuages\u201d and \u201cMinor Swing,\u201d collaborated with Stephane Grapelli and combined jazz with his native Romani music. A concerto for this instrument was inspired by the palace gardens of King Philip II in Aranjuez [air-an-weth]</b> <b>and was written by (+)</b> <b>Joaquin [wha-keen] Rodrigo. A performer of this instrument was</b> <b>inspired by the fight against Hitler to decorate his with the phrase \u201cThis Machine (*)</b> Kills Fascists.\u201d Django Reinhardt and the writer of \u201cThis Land Is Your Land,\u201d Woody Guthrie, both played, for ten points, what instrument that has six strings and frets?", "answer": "<b> guitar</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {}, {}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}